<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
	  <important>
	  <para>
	    You should include the following environment variables in your shell
	    configuration file. (example <filename>$HOME/.bashrc</filename>)
	  </para>
	  </important>

	  <para>
	  In order to set the user environment, follow these steps:
	  <orderedlist>

	    <listitem>
	    <para>
	    Set up Globus user environment:
	    <screen>$ source $GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-user-env.sh</screen>
	    </para>
	    <para>
	    or
	    <screen>$ . $GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-user-env.csh</screen>
	    </para>
	    <para>
	    depending on the shell you are using.
	    </para>
	    </listitem>

	    <listitem>
	    <para>
	    Set up the GridWay user environment:
	    <screen>
	$ export GW_LOCATION=&lt;path_to_GridWay_installation>
	$ export PATH=$PATH:$GW_LOCATION/bin</screen>
	    </para>
	    <para>
	    or
	    <screen>
	$ setenv GW_LOCATION &lt;path_to_GW_location>
	$ setenv PATH $PATH:$GW_LOCATION/bin</screen>
	    </para>
	    <para>
	    depending on the shell you are using.
	    </para>
	    </listitem>

	    <listitem>
	    <para>
	    Optionally, you can set up your environment to use the GridWay
	    DRMAA library:
	    <screen>
	$ export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$LD_LIBRARY_PATH:$GW_LOCATION/lib</screen>
	    </para>
	    <para>
	    or: <screen>
	$ setenv LD_LIBRARY_PATH $LD_LIBRARY_PATH:$GW_LOCATION/lib</screen>
	    </para>
	    </listitem>

	    <listitem>
	    <para>
	    If GridWay has been compiled with accounting support, you may need
	    to set up the DB library. For example, if DB library has been installed in
	    <filename>/usr/local/BerkeleyDB.4.4</filename>:
	    <screen>$ export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$LD_LIBRARY_PATH:/usr/local/BerkeleyDB.4.4/lib</screen>
	    </para>
	    <note>
	    <para>
	    This step is only needed if your environment has not been configured, ask
	    your administrator.
	    </para>
	    </note>
	    </listitem>


	<listitem>
			<para>
				DRMAA extensions for all the languages use the dynamic drmaa libraries provided by GridWay. To use this libraries it is needed to tell the operating system where to look for them. Here are described the steps needed to do this in Linux and MacOS X.
			</para>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					1. In linux we have two ways to do this, one is using environment variables and the other one is modifying systemwide library path configuration. You only need to use one of this methods. If you do not have root access to the machine you are using or you do not want to setup it for every user in your system you have to use the environment variable method.
				</para>
			    </listitem>
				
				<listitem>
			   <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
						1.1 The environment variable you have to set so the extensions find the required DRMAA library is LD_LIBRARY_PATH with a line similar to:
					</para>

					<screen>
export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$GW_LOCATION/lib</screen>

					<para>
						If you want to setup this systemwide you can put this line alongside <envar>GW_LOCATION</envar> setup into <filename>/etc/profile</filename>. If you do not have root access or you want to do it per user the best place to do it is in the user's <filename>.bashrc</filename>.
					</para>

					<para>
						You can also do this steps in the console before launching your scripts as it will have the same effect.
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
				

					<para>
						Systems that use GNU/libc (GNU/Linux is one of them) do have a systemwide configuration file with the paths where to look for dynamic libraries. You have to add this line to <filename>/etc/ld.so.conf</filename>:
					</para>

					<screen>
&lt;path_to_gridway_installation&gt;/lib</screen>

					<para>
						After doing this you have to rebuild the library cache issuing this command:
					</para>

					<screen>
# ldconfig</screen>			
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
    	</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				In MacOS X you have to use the environment variable method described for Linux but this time the name of the variable is <envar>DYLD_LIBRARY_PATH</envar>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
	  </para>
</section>