<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>
 GridWay is an open project, flexible and completely based on standards to leverage its usability and interoperability. GridWay supports several standards developed by the <ulink
url="http://www.ogf.org"> Open Grid Forum.</ulink>, namely:
</para>

<variablelist>
  <varlistentry>
  <term>Distributed Resource Management Application API Working Group
(DRMAA-WG)</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>The <ulink url="http://drmaa.org/wiki/">DRMAA working group</ulink>
 has developed an API specification for the submission and control of jobs to
one or more Distributed Resource Management (DRM) systems. The goal is to
facilitate the direct interfacing of applications to today's DRM systems by
application's builders, portal builders, and Independent Software Vendors
(ISVs). The Distributed Resource Management Application API (DRMAA) provides a
generalized API to distributed resource management systems (DRMSs) in order to
facilitate integration of application programs.</para>

    <para>The scope of DRMAA is limited to job submission, job monitoring
and control, and retrieval of the finished job status. DRMAA provides
application developers and distributed resource management builders with a
programming model that enables the development of distributed applications
tightly coupled to an underlying DRMS. DRMAA preserves flexibility and choice in
system design.</para>

  <para>GridWay provides support for the DRMAA API (JAVA and C
bindings) to develop distributed applications. <ulink
url="http://www.ogf.org/documents/GFD.104.pdf">OGF document GFD.104:
GridWay DRMAA 1.0 Implementation - Experience Report</ulink> provides details of
the implementation.</para>
  </listitem>
  </varlistentry>

  <varlistentry>
  <term>Job Submission Description Language (JSDL-WG)</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>The goal of the <ulink
url="http://forge.gridforum.org/sf/projects/jsdl-wg">JSDL working group</ulink>
is to produce a language that describes the requirements of jobs for submission
to Grids. JSDL 1.0, <ulink
url="http://www.ggf.org/documents/GFD.56.pdf">published as OGF recommendation
GFD-R-P.056</ulink>  is an XML-based language that focuses mainly on
computational jobs. The JSDL-WG is working on extending this language to address
a wider class of jobs, including Web service invocations.</para>

    <para>Last GridWay release provides support for JSDL, the POSIX Application
profile and HTC Profile schemas can be used to describe jobs.</para>
  </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
</variablelist>
</section>