<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>Since GridWay 5.2, development activities have been focused on easing the
integration of GridWay with the major Grid infrastructures: EGEE, TeraGrid and
OSG. As a result, the flexibility of GridWay has been considerably improved. In
addition, an important effort has been made to improve the reliability of
GridWay's core.</para>

<para>Also, GridWay 5.2.1 is the first release shipped with the Globus
Toolkit. Therefore, some modifications have been introduced to build and install
GridWay in a GT tree: the directory layout has been slighly changed, and
support to build GridWay with GPT has been added.</para>

<para>New to GridWay 5.2.1:</para>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry>
  <term>Integration with major Grid Infrastructures</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>GridWay 5.2.1 can be easily integrated with all the major Grid
infrastructures. Its functionality has been extended to operate different Grid
deployments, which includes support for different execution/transfer schemes,
information models and service configurations.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Improved Reliability</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>Previous GridWay releases do not handle MAD crashes. GridWay 5.2.1
will reload a MAD process whenever a MAD is killed or crashed.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>New Information model</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>The dynamic information of a host gathered from the Grid Information
server can be mixed with custom variables defined by the GridWay administrator.
This functionality is very useful when you need to extend the information scheme
but have no access to the Grid server. For example, you can use this new feature
to add software or license attributes to grid resources that can 
subsequently be used for resource requirement expressions.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Configuration Interface for MADs</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>Middleware Access Drivers need some environment variables to work
properly. Usually, sudo must be configured to preserve these variables (e.g.
<computeroutput>GLOBUS_LOCATION</computeroutput> or
<computeroutput>GW_LOCATION</computeroutput>). GridWay 5.2.1 has a new
configuration interface to ease this configuration. In this way, global (and per
user) environment variables can be defined for MAD execution. This new feature
allows GridWay to work with delegated credentials when configured with a GRAM
interface.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Flexible definition of file transfer servers</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>A GridFTP server, different from the GRAM server, can be defined for
file staging. The storage server must be defined
(<computeroutput>SE_HOSTNAME</computeroutput>, attribute) for those resources
operated on in this way. This can be done either by modifying the IM's MAD or using
the new static-dynamic information model.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Support for JSDL HPC profile </term>
  <listitem>
    <para>Now job templates can be also defined using the OGF standard JSDL HPC
profile.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>
</section>