<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>

<section>

<para>This guide contains
  installation and configuration information for system administrators installing
GridWay. It explains how to install, configure and test the installation. </para>
    <important>
        <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite,
          overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <ulink url="admin/admin/admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>.
          Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>
    </important>

		<section>
			<title>GridWay Architecture</title>

	    <figure>
	      <title>Components of the GridWay Meta-scheduler.</title>
	      <graphic align="center" fileref="admin/gw_arch.jpg"/>
	    </figure>

	    <para>
	    GridWay 5 architecture consists of the following components:
	    </para>

	    <para>
	    <itemizedlist>
	      <listitem>
	      <para>
	      <emphasis>User Interface</emphasis> provides the end user with DRM-like
	      commands to submit, kill, migrate, monitor and synchronize jobs and
	      includes DRMAA (Distributed Resource Management Application API) GGF
	      (Global Grid Forum) standard support to develop distributed applications
	      (C and JAVA bindings).
	      </para>
	      </listitem>

	      <listitem>
	      <para>
	      <emphasis>GridWay core</emphasis> is responsible for job execution
	      management and resource brokering, providing advanced scheduling, and job
	      failure &amp; recovery capabilities. The Dispatch Manager performs all
	      submission stages and watches over the efficient execution of the job. The
	      Information Manager, through its MADs (Middleware Access Driver), is
	      responsible for host discovery and monitoring. The Execution Manager,
	      through its MADs, is responsible job execution and management. The
	      Transfer Manager, through its MADs, is responsible for file staging,
	      remote working directory set-up and remote host clean-up.
	      </para>
	      </listitem>

	      <listitem>
	      <para>
	      <emphasis>Scheduler</emphasis> makes scheduling decisions for jobs on
	      available resources.
	      </para>
	      </listitem>

	      <listitem>
	      <para>
	      <emphasis>Information Manager MAD</emphasis> interfaces with the monitoring
	      and discovering services available in the Grid infrastructure.
	      </para>
	      </listitem>

	      <listitem>
	      <para>
	      <emphasis>Execution Manager MAD</emphasis> interfaces with the Job
	      Management Services available in the Grid resources.
	      </para>
	      </listitem>

	      <listitem>
	      <para>
	      <emphasis>Transfer Manager MAD</emphasis> interfaces with the Data
	      Management Services available in the Grid resources.
	      </para>
	      </listitem>
	    </itemizedlist>
	    </para>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Meta-scheduling Infrastructures with GridWay</title>
			
			  <section>
			    <title>Enterprise Grid Infrastructures</title>

			      <para>
			      Enterprise grids enable diverse resource sharing to improve internal collaboration and achieve a better return from information technology investment. Available resources within a company are better exploited and the administrative overhead is minimized by using Grid technology. The resources are part of the same administrative domain. Theses infrastructures require a centralized approach for scheduling and accounting. The administrator must be able to apply centralized usage policies and access to global reporting and accounting. Enterprise grid infrastructures require meta-schedulers to provide support for multiple users in a single scheduling instance. 
			      </para>

			      <figure>
			        <title>Enterprise Grid deployment with GridWay.</title>
			        <graphic align="center" fileref="admin/gw_enterprise.png"/>
			      </figure>
			    </section>

			<section>
	    <title>Partner Grid Infrastructures</title>

	      <para>
	      Partner grid infrastructures of several scales are being deployed within the context of different research projects, whose final goal is to provide large-scale, secure and reliable sharing of resources among partner organizations and supply-chain participants. Such partner grids allow access to a higher computing performance to satisfy peak demands and also provide support to face collaborative projects. The multiple administration domains existing in a partner grid infrastructure prevent the deployment of centralized meta-schedulers, with total control over client requests and resource status. Organization-level meta-schedulers provide support for multiple intra-organization users in each scheduling instance. This means that there is one scheduling instance for each organization, and all scheduling instances compete with each other for the available resources.
	      </para>
	      <figure>
	        <title>Partner Grid deployment with GridWay.</title>
	        <graphic align="center" fileref="admin/gw_partner.png"/>
	      </figure>
	    </section>
		
		<section>
			<title>Federation of Grid Infrastructures</title>
			<para>
		Please visit the web page about <ulink url="http://www.gridway.org/research/gridfederation.php">Federation of Grid Infrastructures and Utility Computing</ulink> to find out how to deploy federated grid infrastructures using Globus and GridWay. A WS-GRAM service hosting a GridWay meta-scheduler provides the standard functionality required to implement a gateway to a federated grid. That is to virtualize a whole grid, providing a powerful abstraction of the underlying grid resource management services. </para>
		  <figure>
	        <title>Grid Federation with GridWay and GridGateWays.</title>
	        <graphic align="center" fileref="admin/gw_federation.png"/>
	      </figure>
			</section>
		</section>
   </section>
