<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>
Starting with version 4.0.5, GT includes the GridWay Metascheduler, which enables large-scale, reliable and efficient sharing of
computing resources (clusters , computing farms, servers, supercomputers...),
managed by different LRM (Local Resource Management) systems, such as PBS, SGE,
LSF, Condor..., within a single organization (enterprise grid) or scattered
across several administrative domains (partner or supply-chain grid).
</para>

<para>
There exist a number of commercial and open source workload management and
scheduling systems available today, each one suitable for different underlying
computer infrastructures and execution profiles. GridWay stands out from other
metascheduling systems because it has been specifically designed to work on top
of Globus services, offering the highest functionality, quality of service and
reliability on this kind of infrastructure, namely:
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="strong">For project and infrastructure directors:
      </emphasis> GridWay is an open-source community project, adhering to
      Globus philosophy and guidelines for collaborative development.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="strong">For system integrators:</emphasis> GridWay
is highly modular, allowing
      adaptation to different grid infrastructures, and supports several OGF
      standards.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="strong">For system managers:</emphasis> GridWay
      provides a scheduling framework similar to
      that found on local LRM systems, supporting resource accounting and the
      definition of state-of-the-art scheduling policies.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="strong">For application developers:</emphasis>
GridWay implements the OGF standard
      DRMAA API (C and JAVA bindings), assuring compatibility between applications
      with LRM systems that implement the standard, such as SGE,
      Condor, Torque...etc.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="strong">For end users:</emphasis> GridWay provides an
        LRM-like CLI for submitting, monitoring, synchronizing and
        controlling jobs, that could be described using the OGF
        standard JSDL.</para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
GridWay gives end users, application developers and managers of Globus
infrastructures a scheduling functionality similar to that found on local DRM
systems.
</para>
</section>