<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<variablelist>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Advanced Scheduling Capabilities</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>
      GridWay implements several state-of-the-art Grid-aware scheduling
policies, comprising <emphasis>job prioritization</emphasis> policies (fixed
priority, urgency, share, deadline and waiting-time) and <emphasis>resource
prioritization</emphasis> policies (fixed priority, usage, failure and rank).
  </para>
  <para>
These policies are combined with:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><emphasis>Adaptive Scheduling</emphasis>, to
periodically adapt the schedule considering applications' demands and Grid
resource characteristics.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis>Adaptive Execution</emphasis> to migrate
running applications in terms of resource availability, capacity or cost, and
new application requirements or preferences.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Transparent Grid Access</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    GridWay interfaces infrastructures with
different middleware stacks. With GridWay, users can access heterogeneous
resources in a transparent way. For example, it can access resources configured
with both GRAM pre web services and GRAM web services. It also permits the use
of different grids with different software stacks, for example, Teragrid with
Globus and EGEE with gLite.
    </para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>


<varlistentry>
  <term>Flexible Deployment Capabilities</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    GridWay supports multiple-user operation mode, and does not require
additional middleware installation (apart from standard Globus services). Globus
installation is not required in each end-user system.
    </para>

    <para>
     GridWay allows different Grid deployment strategies, like Enterprise Grids,
Partner Grids or Utility Grids.
    </para>

  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Different Application Profiles</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>GridWay executes different Grid application profiles:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Array (Bulk) jobs, for parameter sweep
applications</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>DAG Workflows</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Single-site MPI applications</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Fault Detection and Recovery</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>GridWay is able to detect several problems that can occur when
executing a remote job. It also implements mechanisms that make the execution
more reliable. It can detect a remote system crash, a job failure (via the job
exit code) or even a network disconnection (using the polling mechanism) and
migrate the problematic job to another resource.</para><para>GridWay also
performs periodic saves of its state in order to recover from local
failure.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Reporting and Accounting</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>GridWay provides detailed statistics of Grid usage. In this
way, the Grid administrator can properly plan usage policies and forecast
workload. In addition, these statistics can be used by the scheduler to
predict (per user) Grid resource response time.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>Standard Compliance</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>GridWay is an open-source project, flexible and completely based on standards
to leverage its usability and interoperability. For example, users can describe
their jobs using JSDL. Similarly, programmers can build grid
enabled applications using the DRMAA standard.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
  <term>User Interface</term>
  <listitem>
    <para>GridWay provides end-users with a familiar environment similar
to that found on classical LRM systems. So GridWay CLI eases the adoption
of Grid technologies.</para>
  </listitem>
</varlistentry>

</variablelist>
</section>