<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary
PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
                    [
                    
                    <!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "entities">
                    
                    %myents;
                    
                    ]>
<glossary id="toolkit-glossary"><title>GT &version; Glossary</title>
      <!-- includes glossary excerpts from all the standards definitions in the WS-ServiceGroup specification 
      see "Terminology and Concepts" in "http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ServiceGroup-1.2-draft-02.pdf".  
      
      setting up glossary database throughout a version's set of books, as outlined here:
      http://www.sagehill.net/docbookxsl/GlossDatabase.html 
      (requires at least version 1.68 of the DocBook XSL stylesheets and version 4.4 of the DocBook XML DTD)
      
    -->
      <glossdiv>
            <title>A</title>
            <glossentry id="aggregator-framework">
                  <glossterm>Aggregator Framework</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A software framework used to build services that collect and aggregate
                              data. MDS4 Services (such as the Index and Trigger services) are built
                              on the Aggregator Framework, and are sometimes called Aggregator
                              Services.</para>
                        <para>[olink to agg framework doc]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="aggregator-services">
                  <glossterm>aggregator services</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Services that are built on the Aggregator Framework, such as the MDS4
                              Index Service and Trigger Service.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="aggregator-source">
                  <glossterm>aggregator source</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A Java class that implements an interface (defined as part of the
                              Aggregator Framework) to collect XML-formatted data. MDS4 contains
                              three aggregator sources: the query aggregator source, the
                              subscription aggregator source, and the execution aggregator
                        source.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="ant">
                  <glossterm>Ant</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Apache Open Source Java based build tool. [needed to install, olink to
                              install guide?]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="axis">
                  <glossterm>Apache Axis</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The SOAP engine implementation used within the Globus Toolkit. See the
                                    <ulink url="http://ws.apache.org/axis/">Apache Axis
                              website</ulink> for details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="apache-commons">
                  <glossterm>Apache Commons</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[what does this have to do with GT?]. See <ulink
                                    url="http://jakarta.apache.org/commons/"
                                    >http://jakarta.apache.org/commons/</ulink> for more
                        details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="autoconf">
                  <glossterm>autoconf</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>GNU Open Source package used to automatically configure the source
                              code package. [olink to install guide?]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="automake">
                  <glossterm>automake</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>GNU Open Source used to automatically generate Makefile in files.
                              [olink to install guide?]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="axis-c">
                  <glossterm>Axis C++</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Open Source SOAP implementation used by C-Hosting. See <ulink
                                    url="http://ws.apache.org/axis/cpp">
                                    http://ws.apache.org/axis/cpp</ulink> for more details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>B</title>
            <glossentry id="batch-scheduler">
                  <glossterm>batch scheduler</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>See the definition for scheduler</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="bloom-filter">
                  <glossterm>Bloom filter</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Compression scheme used by the Replica Location Service (RLS) that is
                              intended to reduce the size of soft state updates between Local
                              Replica Catalogs (LRCs) and Replica Location Index (RLI) servers. A
                              Bloom filter is a bit map that summarizes the contents of a Local
                              Replica Catalog (LRC). An LRC constructs the bit map by applying a
                              series of hash functions to each logical name registered in the LRC
                              and setting the corresponding bits.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="bouncy-castle">
                  <glossterm>Bouncy Castle Crypto APIs</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="http://www.bouncycastle.org"
                              >http://www.bouncycastle.org</ulink> (what is this for?) </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>C</title>
            <glossentry id="ca">
                  <glossterm>Certificate Authority</glossterm>
                  <acronym> CA </acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> An entity that issues certificates. [re: security - olink to useful
                              page]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="ca-cert">
                  <glossterm>CA Certificate</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The CA's certificate. This certificate is used to verify signature on
                              certificates issued by the CA. GSI typically stores a given CA
                              certificate in
                                          
<filename>/etc/grid-security/certificates/<replaceable>&lt;hash&gt;</replaceable>.0</filename>,
                              where &lt;hash&gt; is the hash code of the CA identity.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="ca-sign">
                  <glossterm>CA Signing Policy</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The CA signing policy is used to place constraints on the information
                              you trust a given CA to bind to public keys. Specifically it
                              constrains the identities a CA is trusted to assert in a certificate.
                              In GSI the signing policy for a given CA can typically be found in
                                          
<filename>/etc/grid-security/certificates/<replaceable>&lt;hash&gt;</replaceable>.signing_policy</filename>,
                              where &lt;hash&gt; is the hash code of the CA identity. For
                              more information see [add link].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="cert">
                  <glossterm>certificate</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A public key plus information about the certificate owner bound
                              together by the digital signature of a CA. In the case of a CA
                              certificate, the certificate is self signed, i.e. it was signed using
                              its own private key.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="crl">
                  <glossterm>Certificate Revocation List</glossterm>
                  <acronym>CRL</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A list of revoked certificates generated by the CA that originally
                              issued them. When using GSI [not really defined in gt4...] this list
                              is typically found in
                                          
<filename>/etc/grid-security/certificates/<replaceable>&lt;hash&gt;</replaceable>.r0</filename>,
                              where &lt;hash&gt; is the hash code of the CA identity.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="cert-subject">
                  <glossterm>certificate subject</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> An identifier for the certificate owner, e.g.
                                    "<filename>/DC=org/DC=doegrids/OU=People/CN=John Doe
                              123456</filename>". The subject is part of the information the CA
                              binds to a public key when creating a certificate.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="client">
                  <glossterm>client</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[too specific to data - more details or more general] FTP is a
                              command/response protocol. The defining characteristic of a client is
                              that it is the process sending the commands and receiving the
                              responses. It may or may not take part in the actual movement of data.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="client-config.wsdd">
                  <glossterm>client-config.wsdd</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Axis client-side WSDD configuration file. It contains information
                              about the type mappings, the transport and other handlers. [need a
                              little more info tying it to Core...] </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="client-server-transfer">
                  <glossterm>client/server transfer</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>In a client/server transfer, there are only two entities involved in
                              the transfer, the client entity and the server entity. We use the term
                              entity here rather than process because in the implementation provided
                              in GT4, the server entity may actually run as two or more separate
                              processes. </para>
                        <para>The client will either move data from or to his local host. The client
                              will decide whether or not he wishes to connect to the server to
                              establish the data channel or the server should connect to him (MODE E
                              dictates who must connect).</para>
                        <para>If the client wishes to connect to the server, he will send the PASV
                              (passive) command. The server will start listening on an ephemeral
                              (random, non-privileged) port and will return the IP and port as a
                              response to the command. The client will then connect to that IP/Port. </para>
                        <para>If the client wishes to have the server connect to him, the client
                              would start listening on an ephemeral port, and would then send the
                              PORT command which includes the IP/Port as part of the command to the
                              server and the server would initiate the TCP connect. Note that this
                              decision has an impact on traversing firewalls. For instance, the
                              client's host may be behind a firewall and the server may not be able
                              to connect. </para>
                        <para>Finally, now that the data channel is established, the client will
                              send either the RETR a?filenamea command to transfer a file from the
                              server to the client (GET), or the STOR a?filenamea command to transfer
                              a file from the client to the server (PUT). </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="command-response">
                  <glossterm>command/response</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> [can't find this term anywhere in gridftp docs] Both FTP and GridFTP
                              are command/response protocols. What this means is that once a client
                              sends a command to the server, it can only accept responses from the
                              server until it receives a response indicating that the server is
                              finished with that command. For most commands this is not a big deal.
                              For instance, setting the type of the file transfer to binary (called
                              "I" for "image in the protocol"), simply consists of the client
                              sending TYPE I and the server responding with 220 OK. Type set to I.
                              However, the SEND and RETR commands (which actually initiate the
                              movement of data) can run for a long time. Once the command is sent,
                              the clientas only options are to wait until it receives the completion
                              reply, or kill the transfer. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="concurrency">
                  <glossterm>concurrency</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> [can't find this term anywhere in gridftp docs] When speaking of
                              GridFTP transfers, concurrency refers to having multiple files in
                              transit at the same time. They may all be on the same host or across
                              multiple hosts. This is equivalent to starting up a?na different
                              clients for a?na different files, and having them all running at the
                              same time. This can be effective if you have many small files to move.
                              The Reliable File Transfer (RFT) service utilizes concurrency to
                              improve its performance.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="condor">
                  <glossterm>Condor</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A job scheduler mechanism supported by GRAM. See <ulink
                                    url="http://www.cs.wisc.edu/condor/"
                                    >http://www.cs.wisc.edu/condor/</ulink> for more
                        information.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="container">
                  <glossterm>container</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Also referred to as the "hosting environment." Provides a common
                              runtime environment for web services. It manages the execution of
                              services and resources, and manages their lifecycles. Provides
                              security and data persistence infrasturcure, and other functionality
                              such as managed threading and registry.</para>
                        <para>A default "standalone" container is provided with a default GT
                              installation.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="cred">
                  <glossterm>credentials</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[more details or links] The combination of a certificate and the
                              matching private key.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="cryptix">
                  <glossterm>Cryptix</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="https://www.cryptix.org">https://www.cryptix.org</ulink>
                              [re: what?] </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="cvs">
                  <glossterm>Concurrent Version System</glossterm>
                  <acronym>CVS</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Source code repository used by the Globus Toolkit. [olink to
                              instructions for using cvs with warning that this is for advanced
                              developers...]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>D</title>
            <glossentry id="dual-channel-protocol">
                  <glossterm>dual channel protocol</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> [this term does not appear anywhere in the gridftp docs] GridFTP uses
                              two channels: </para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                              <listitem>
                                    <simpara>One of the channels, called the control channel, is
                                          used for sending commands and responses. It is low
                                          bandwidth and is encrypted for security reasons.
                                    </simpara>
                              </listitem>
                              <listitem>
                                    <simpara>The second channel is known as the data channel. Its
                                          sole purpose is to transfer the data. It is high bandwidth
                                          and uses an efficient protocol. </simpara>
                              </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <para>By default, the data channel is authenticated at connection time, but
                              no integrity checking or encryption is performed due to performance
                              reasons. Integrity checking and encryption are both available via the
                              client and libraries. </para>
                        <para>Note that in GridFTP (not FTP) the data channel may actually consist
                              of several TCP streams from multiple hosts. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>E</title>
            <glossentry id="eec">
                  <glossterm>End Entity Certificate</glossterm>
                  <acronym>EEC</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A certificate belonging to a non-CA entity, e.g. you, me or the
                              computer on your desk.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="execution-aggregator-source">
                  <glossterm>execution aggregator source</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> An Aggregator Source (included in MDS4) that executes an
                              administrator-supplied program to collect information and make it
                              available to an Aggregator Service such as the Index Service.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="exolab">
                  <glossterm>Exolab Core</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="http://www.exolab.org/">http://www.exolab.org/</ulink>
                              [what does this have to do with gt?] </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="extended-block-mode">
                  <glossterm>extended block mode (MODE E)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> MODE E is a critical GridFTP components because it allows for out of
                              order reception of data. This in turn, means we can send the data down
                              multiple paths and do not need to worry if one of the paths is slower
                              than the others and the data arrives out of order. This enables
                              parallelism and striping within GridFTP. In MODE E, a series of
                              a?blocksa are sent over the data channel. Each block consists of:</para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                              <listitem>
                                    <simpara>an 8 bit flag field, </simpara>
                              </listitem>
                              <listitem>
                                    <simpara>a 64 bit field indicating the offset in the
                                    transfer,</simpara>
                              </listitem>
                              <listitem>
                                    <simpara>and a 64 bit field indicating the length of the
                                          payload, </simpara>
                              </listitem>
                              <listitem>
                                    <simpara>followed by length bytes of payload. </simpara>
                              </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <para>Note that since the offset and length are included in the block, out
                              of order reception is possible, as long as the receiving side can
                              handle it, either via something like a seek on a file, or via some
                              application level buffering and ordering logic that will wait for the
                              out of order blocks. [TODO: LINK TO GRAPHIC]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>F</title>
            <glossentry id="flavor">
                  <glossterm>flavor</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Pre-OGSI Globus description term that uniquely encompasses Machine
                              Architecture, OS, Compiler and other attributes into a single term,
                              for example: gcc32dbgpthr for a threaded Linux debug
                        distribution.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="fork">
                  <glossterm>fork</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Terms used to refer to a Unix fork, supported MJS scheduler
                        mechanism.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>G</title>
            <glossentry id="gaa-config">
                  <glossterm>GAA configuration file</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A file that configures the Generic Authorization and Access control
                                    <acronym>GAA</acronym> libraries. When using GSI [term not well
                              described in gt4], this file is typically found in
                                    <filename>/etc/grid-security/gsi-gaa.conf</filename>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="ganglia">
                  <glossterm>Ganglia</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A cluster monitoring tool (re: MDS4). See <ulink
                                    url="http://ganglia.sourceforge.net"
                                    >http://ganglia.sourceforge.net</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="GAR">
                  <glossterm>GAR</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The GAR (Grid ARchive) file is a single file which contains all the
                              files and information that the container needs to deploy a service.
                              See the Java WS Core Developer's Guide for details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="globusrunws">
                  <glossterm>globusrun-ws</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A command line program used to submit jobs to a GRAM4 service. See the
                              the GRAM4 Commandline page.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="gram">
                  <glossterm>Grid Resource Allocation and Management (GRAM)</glossterm>
                  <acronym>GRAM</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[FIXME: copy info from overview brief]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="grid-map-file">
                  <glossterm>grid map file</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A file containing entries mapping certificate subjects to local user
                              names. This file can also serve as a access control list for GSI
                              enabled services and is typically found in
                                    <filename>/etc/grid-security/grid-mapfile</filename>. For more
                              information see the [Gridmap file in Pre-WS Authorization &amp;
                              Authentication Developer's Guide ("Environmental Variables"
                        section)].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="grid-sec-dir">
                  <glossterm>grid security directory</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The directory containing GSI configuration files such as the GSI
                              authorization callout configuration and GAA configuration files.
                              Typically this directory is <filename>/etc/grid-security</filename>.
                              For more information see [Grid security directory in Pre-WS
                              Authorization &amp; Authentication Developer's Guide
                              ("Environmental Variables" section)].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="gsi">
                  <glossterm>Grid Security Infrastructure</glossterm>
                  <acronym>GSI</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>FIXME</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="gsi-authz-config">
                  <glossterm>GSI authorization callout configuration file</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A file that configures authorization callouts to be used for mapping
                              and authorization in GSI enabled services. When using GSI this file is
                              typically found in
                              <filename>/etc/grid-security/gsi-authz.conf</filename>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>H</title>
            <glossentry id="hawkeye">
                  <glossterm>Hawkeye</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A monitoring service for Condor Pools. See <ulink
                                    url="http://www.cs.wisc.edu/condor/hawkeye/"
                                    >http://www.cs.wisc.edu/condor/hawkeye/</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="host-cert">
                  <glossterm>host certificate</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> An EEC belonging to a host. When using GSI this certificate is
                              typically stored in
                              <filename>/etc/grid-security/hostcert.pem</filename>. For more
                              information on possible host certificate locations see the [Pre-WS
                              Authentication &amp; Authorization Developer's Guide
                              ("Environmental Variables" section) on Credentials]. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="host-cred">
                  <glossterm>host credentials</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The combination of a host certificate and its corresponding private
                              key.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="hosting-env">
                  <glossterm>hosting environment</glossterm>
                  <glosssee>container</glosssee>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>I</title>
            <glossentry id="improved-extended-block-mode">
                  <glossterm>improved extended block mode (MODE X)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[this term does not appear anywhere in the gridftp docs] This protocol
                              is still under development. It is intended to address a number of the
                              deficiencies found in MODE E. For instance, it will have explicit
                              negotiation for use of a data channel, thus removing the race
                              condition and the requirement for the sender to be the connector. This
                              will help with firewall traversal. A method will be added to allow the
                              filename to be provided prior to the data channel connection being
                              established to help large data farms better allocate resources. Other
                              additions under consideration include block checksumming, resends of
                              blocks that fail checksums, and inclusion of a transfer ID to allow
                              pipelining and de-multiplexing of commands. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="index-service">
                  <glossterm>Index Service</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>An aggregator service in MDS4 that serves as a registry similar to
                              UDDI, but much more flexible. Indexes collect information and publish
                              that information as WSRF resource properties.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="information-provider">
                  <glossterm>information provider</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A "helper" software component that collects or formats resource
                              information, for use in MDS4 by an aggregator source or by a WSRF
                              service when creating resource properties.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>J</title>
            <glossentry id="javadocs">
                  <glossterm>Javadocs</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Java-generated documentation files. The Globus Toolkit distribution
                              uses this tool to automatically generate API documentation from the
                              code itself. [add olink to api]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="jax-rpc">
                  <glossterm>JAX-RPC</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="http://www.apache.org">http://www.apache.org</ulink> (re:
                              what in GT?) </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="jndi">
                  <glossterm>JNDI</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Java Naming and Directory Interface (JNDI) API are used to access a
                              central transient container registry. The registry is mainly used for
                              discovery of the <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis> implementations.
                              However, the registry can also be used store and retrieve arbitrary
                              information. The <emphasis>jndi-config.xml</emphasis> files are used
                              to populate the registry. See the <ulink
                                    url="http://java.sun.com/products/jndi/tutorial/">JNDI
                              Tutorial</ulink> for details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="jndi-config.xml">
                  <glossterm>jndi-config.xml</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> It is an XML-based configuration file used to populate the container
                              registry accessible via the JNDI API. See in the Java WS Core
                              Developer's Guide] for details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="job-description">
                  <glossterm>job description</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Term used to describe a GRAM4 job for GT4.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="job-scheduler">
                  <glossterm>job scheduler</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>See the term <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#scheduler"
                                    >scheduler</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="junit">
                  <glossterm>JUnit</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Java testing framework.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="jvm">
                  <glossterm>Java Virtual Machine</glossterm>
                  <acronym>JVM</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The Java Runtime under which OGSI modules run.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>L</title>
            <glossentry id="libtool">
                  <glossterm>Libtool</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Libtool is a GNU library support script that abstracts shared library
                              interface. Used by GSI/Sysconfig. Libtool hides the complexity of
                              using shared libraries behind a portable interface.</para>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://www.gnu.org/software/libtool"
                                    >http://www.gnu.org/software/libtool</ulink>.</para>
                        <para>See also <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#gsi"
                        >GSI</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="lrc">
                  <glossterm>Local Replica Catalog (LRC)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Stores mappings between logical names for data items and the target
                              names (often the physical locations) of replicas of those items.
                              Clients query the LRC to discover replicas associated with a logical
                              name. Also may associate attributes with logical or target names. Each
                              LRC periodically sends information about its logical name mappings to
                              one or more RLIs. </para>
                        <para>See also <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#rli"
                        >RLI</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="log4j">
                  <glossterm>Log4J</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="http://www.apache.org">http://www.apache.org</ulink> (re:
                              what in gt4?) </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="logical-file-name">
                  <glossterm>logical file name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A unique identifier for the contents of a file.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="logical-name">
                  <glossterm>logical name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A unique identifier for the contents of a data item. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="lsf">
                  <glossterm>LSF</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A job scheduler mechanism supported by GRAM.</para>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://www.platform.com/Products/Platform.LSF.Family/Platform.LSF/"
                                    >
                                    http://www.platform.com/Products/Platform.LSF.Family/Platform.LSF/</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>M</title>
            <glossentry id="meta-scheduler">
                  <glossterm>metascheduler</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[no mention of this term in any of the documentation...] A program
                              that typically operates at a higher level than a job scheduler
                              (typically, above the GRAM level). It schedules and submits jobs to
                              GRAM services.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="mejs">
                  <glossterm>Managed Executable Job Service</glossterm>
                  <acronym>MEJS</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[FIXME]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="mjfs">
                  <glossterm>Managed Job Factory Service</glossterm>
                  <acronym>MJFS</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[FIXME]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="mmjs">
                  <glossterm>Managed Multi Job Service</glossterm>
                  <acronym>MMJS</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[FIXME]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="mmjs-subjob">
                  <glossterm>MMJS subjob</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[ phrase does not appear in documentation] One of the executable jobs
                              in a multijob rendezvous. (re: GRAM)</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="mpi">
                  <glossterm>Message Passing Interface</glossterm>
                  <acronym>MPI</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The Message Passing Interface (MPI) is a library specification for
                              message-passing, proposed as a standard by a broadly based committee
                              of vendors, implementors, and users.</para>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://www-unix.mcs.anl.gov/mpi/"
                                    >http://www-unix.mcs.anl.gov/mpi/</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="mode-command">
                  <glossterm>MODE command</glossterm>
                  <!-- not sure which instances of the word 'mode' to code -->
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> In reality, GridFTP is not one protocol, but a collection of several
                              protocols. There is a protocol used on the control channel, but there
                              is a range of protocols available for use on the data channel. Which
                              protocol is used is selected by the MODE command. Four modes are
                              defined: STREAM (S), BLOCK (B), COMPRESSED (C) in RFC 959 for FTP, and
                              EXTENDED BLOCK (E) in GFD.020 for GridFTP. There is also a new data
                              channel protocol, or mode, being defined in the GGF GridFTP Working
                              group which, for lack of a better name at this point, is called MODE
                              X. </para>
                        <para>See also <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#extended-block-mode"
                                    >extended block mode (MODE E)</ulink>.</para>
                        <para>See also <ulink
                                    url="&docpath;glossary.html#improved-extended-block-mode"
                                    >improved extended block mode (MODE X)</ulink>.</para>
                        <para>See also <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#stream-mode">stream
                                    mode (MODE S)</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="multijob">
                  <glossterm>multijob</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A job that is itself composed of several executable jobs; these are
                              processed by the MMJS subjob.</para>
                        <para>See also <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#mmjs-subjob">MMJS
                                    subjob</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="multijob-rendezvous">
                  <glossterm>multijob rendezvous</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[phrase not used in documentation] A mechanism used by GRAM to
                              synchronize between job processes in a multiprocess job and
                        between.</para>
                  </glossdef>
                  <!--  -->
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>N</title>
            <glossentry id="network-end-points">
                  <glossterm>network end points</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[this term does not appear anywhere in the gridftp docs] A network
                              endpoint is generally something that has an IP address (a network
                              interface card). It is a point of access to the network for
                              transmission or reception of data. Note that a single host could have
                              multiple network end points if it haS multiple NICs installed
                              (multi-homed). This definition is necessary to differentiate between
                              parallelism and striping.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="nfs">
                  <glossterm>Network File System</glossterm>
                  <acronym>NFS</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The Network File System (NFS) provides remote access to shared file
                              systems across networks. </para>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://www.uwsg.iu.edu/usail/network/nfs/overview.html">
                                    http://www.uwsg.iu.edu/usail/network/nfs/overview.html</ulink>.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>O</title>
            <glossentry id="openjms">
                  <glossterm>OpenJMS</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="http://www.exolab.org/">http://www.exolab.org/</ulink>
                              (re: what in gt4?) </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="openldap">
                  <glossterm>OpenLDAP</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url=" http://www.openldap.org"> http://www.openldap.org</ulink>
                              Open Source Lightweight Directory Access Protocol in the C Language.
                        h</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="openssl">
                  <glossterm>OpenSSL</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>SSL implementation used by GSI. Stands for Open Source Secure Sockets
                              Layer. Distribution in the C Language. For more information, see
                                    <ulink url="http://www.openssl.org"
                              >http://www.openssl.org</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="OperationProvider">
                  <glossterm>operation provider</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A reusable Java component that implements one or more web service
                              functions. A web service can be composed of one or more operation
                              providers. See the in the Java WS Core Developer's Guide for details.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>P</title>
            <glossentry id="parallelism">
                  <glossterm>parallelism</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> When speaking about GridFTP transfers, parallelism refers to having
                              multiple TCP connections between a single pair of network endpoints.
                              This is used to improve performance of transfers on connections with
                              light to moderate packet loss.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="pbs">
                  <glossterm>Portable Batch System</glossterm>
                  <acronym>PBS</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A job scheduler mechanism supported by GRAM. For more information, see
                                    <ulink url="http://www.openpbs.org"
                              >http://www.openpbs.org</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="physical-file-name">
                  <glossterm>physical file name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The address or the location of a copy of a file on a storage system.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="priv-key">
                  <glossterm>private key</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The private part of a key pair. Depending on the type of certificate
                              the key corresponds to it may typically be found in
                                    <filename>$HOME/.globus/userkey.pem</filename> (for user
                              certificates), <filename>/etc/grid-security/hostkey.pem</filename>
                              (for host certificates) or
                                          
<filename>/etc/grid-security/<replaceable>&lt;service&gt;</replaceable>/<replaceable>&lt;service&gt;</replaceable>key.pem</filename>
                              (for service certificates).</para>
                        <para>For more information on possible private key locations see
                              [Credentials in the Pre-WS Authentication &amp; Authorization
                              Developer's Guide ("Environmental Variables" section)].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="proxy-cert">
                  <glossterm>proxy certificate</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A short lived certificate issued using a EEC. A proxy certificate
                              typically has the same effective subject as the EEC that issued it and
                              can thus be used in its place. GSI uses proxy certificates for single
                              sign on and delegation of rights to other entities.</para>
                        <para>For more information about types of proxy certificates and their
                              compatibility in different versions of GT, see <ulink
                                    url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/Security/ProxyCertTypes"
                                    >http://dev.globus.org/wiki/Security/ProxyCertTypes</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="proxy-cred">
                  <glossterm>proxy credentials</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The combination of a proxy certificate and its corresponding private
                              key. GSI typically stores proxy credentials in
                                          <filename>/tmp/x509up_u<replaceable>&lt;uid&gt;</replaceable>
                              </filename>, where &lt;uid&gt; is the user id of the proxy
                              owner.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="pub-key">
                  <glossterm>public key</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The public part of a key pair used for cryptographic operations (e.g.
                              signing, encrypting).</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="puretls">
                  <glossterm>PureTLS</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>
                              <ulink url="http://www.rtfm.com/puretls/"
                              >http://www.rtfm.com/puretls/</ulink>
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>Q</title>
            <glossentry id="query-aggregator-source">
                  <glossterm>query aggregator source</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>An aggregator source (included in MDS4) that polls a WSRF service for
                              resource property information.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>R</title>
            <glossentry id="rli">
                  <glossterm>Replica Location Index</glossterm>
                  <acronym>RLI</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Collects information about the logical name mappings stored in one or
                              more Local Replica Catalogs (LRCs) and answers queries about those
                              mappings. Each RLI periodically receives updates from one or more LRCs
                              that summarize their contents.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="rls">
                  <glossterm>Replica Location Service (RLS)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A distributed registry that keeps track of where replicas exist on
                              physical storage systems. The job of the RLS is to maintain
                              associations, or mappings, between logical names for data objects and
                              one or more target or physical names for replicas. Users or services
                              register data items in the RLS and query RLS servers to find
                        replicas.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="resource">
                  <glossterm>resource</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> As part of the WSRF strategy of keeping the web service and the state
                              information separate from each other, the state information is kept in
                              a separate entity called a resource. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="rp">
                  <glossterm>resource properties</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A resource is composed of zero or more resource properties which
                              describe the resource. For example, a resource can have the following
                              three resource properties: Filename, Size, and Descriptors. The
                              resource properties are defined in the web service's WSDL interface
                              description. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="rsl">
                  <glossterm>Resource Specification Language</glossterm>
                  <acronym>RSL</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Term used to describe a GRAM job for GT2 and GT3. (Note: This is not
                              the same as RLS - the Replica Location Service) </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="ResourceHome">
                  <glossterm>ResourceHome</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>In Java WS Core, resources are managed and discovered via
                                    <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis> implementations. The
                                    <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis> implementations can also be
                              responsible for creating new resources, performing operations on a set
                              of resources at a time, etc. <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis>s are
                              configured in JNDI and are associated with a particular web
                        service.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="rls-attribute">
                  <glossterm>RLS attribute</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Descriptive information that may be associated with a logical or
                              target name mapping registered in a Local Replica Catalog (LRC).
                              Clients can query the LRC to discover logical names or target names
                              that have specified RLS attributes.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>S</title>
            <glossentry id="saaj">
                  <glossterm>SAAJ</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[re: what in gt4?] For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://www.apache.org">http://www.apache.org</ulink>.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="sasl">
                  <glossterm>SASL</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Utilized by GSI. Open Source Simple Authentication and Security Layer
                              in the C Language. For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://asg.web.cmu.edu/sasl"
                              >http://asg.web.cmu.edu/sasl</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="scheduler">
                  <glossterm>scheduler</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Term used to describe a job scheduler mechanism to which GRAM
                              interfaces. It is a networked system for submitting, controlling, and
                              monitoring the workload of batch jobs in one or more computers. The
                              jobs or tasks are scheduled for execution at a time chosen by the
                              subsystem according to an available policy and availability of
                              resources. Popular job schedulers include Portable Batch System (PBS),
                              Platform LSF, and IBM LoadLeveler.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="scheduler-adapter">
                  <glossterm>scheduler adapter</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The interface used by GRAM to communicate/interact with a job
                              scheduler mechanism. In GT 4.x, this is both the perl submission
                              scripts and the SEG program.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="seg">
                  <glossterm>Scheduler Event Generator</glossterm>
                  <acronym>SEG</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>[FIXME]</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="server">
                  <glossterm>server</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>The compliment to the client is the server. Its defining
                              characteristic is that it receives commands and sends responses to
                              those commands. Since it is a server or service, and it receives
                              commands, it must be listening on a port somewhere to receive the
                              commands. Both FTP and GridFTP have IANA registered ports. For FTP it
                              is port 21, for GridFTP it is port 2811. This is normally handled via
                              inetd or xinetd on Unix variants. However, it is also possible to
                              implement a daemon that listens on the specified port. This is
                              described more fully in in the [Architecture section of the GridFTP
                              Developer's Guide].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="server-config.wsdd">
                  <glossterm>server-config.wsdd</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Axis server-side WSDD configuration file. It contains information
                              about the services, the type mappings and various handlers.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="service">
                  <glossterm>service</glossterm>
                  <glossdef><para>See <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html#web-service">web
                  service</ulink>.</para></glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="svc-cert">
                  <glossterm>service certificate</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A EEC for a specific service (e.g. FTP or LDAP). When using GSI this
                              certificate is typically stored in
                                          
<filename>/etc/grid-security/<replaceable>&lt;service&gt;</replaceable>/<replaceable>&lt;service&gt;</replaceable>cert.pem</filename>.
                              For more information on possible service certificate locations, see
                              [Credentials in the Pre-WS Authentication &amp; Authorization
                              Developer's Guide ("Environmental Variables" section)].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="svc-cred">
                  <glossterm>service credentials</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The combination of a service certificate and its corresponding
                              private key.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="servlet">
                  <glossterm>servlet</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink url="http://www.apache.org"
                                    >http://www.apache.org</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="soap">
                  <glossterm>SOAP</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> SOAP provides a standard, extensible, composable framework for
                              packaging and exchanging XML messages between a service provider and a
                              service requester. SOAP is independent of the underlying transport
                              protocol, but is most commonly carried on HTTP. See the <ulink
                                    url="http://www.w3.org/TR/soap/">SOAP specifications</ulink> for
                              details. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="standalone">
                  <glossterm>standalone container</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>A simple HTTP server that passes requests to the SOAP engine and it
                              can only serve .wsdl and .xsd files. Included with a standard
                              installation of the Globus Toolkit for use as the build hosting
                              environment for testing or extremely basic deployments. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="stream-mode">
                  <glossterm>stream mode (MODE S)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The only mode normally implemented for FTP is MODE S. This is simply
                              sending each byte, one after another over the socket in order, with no
                              application level framing of any kind. This is the default and is what
                              a standard FTP server will use. This is also the default for GridFTP.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="striping">
                  <glossterm>striping</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> When speaking about GridFTP transfers, striping refers to having
                              multiple network endpoints at the source, destination, or both
                              participating in the transfer of the same file. This is normally
                              accomplished by having a cluster with a parallel shared file system.
                              Each node in the cluster reads a section of the file and sends it over
                              the network. This mode of transfer is necessary if you wish to
                              transfer a single file faster than a single host is capable of. This
                              also tends to only be effective for large files, though how large
                              depends on how many hosts and how fast the end-to-end transfer is.
                              Note that while it is theoretically possible to use NFS for the shared
                              file system, your performance will be poor, and would make using
                              striping pointless. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="subscription-aggregator-source">
                  <glossterm>subscription aggregator source</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>An aggregator source (included in MDS4) that collects data from a WSRF
                              service via WSRF subscription/notification.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="sudo">
                  <glossterm>superuser do</glossterm>
                  <abbrev>sudo</abbrev>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Allows a system administrator to give certain users (or groups of
                              users) the ability to run some (or all) commands as root or another
                              user while logging the commands and arguments. See <ulink
                                    url="http://www.courtesan.com/sudo/"
                                    >http://www.courtesan.com/sudo/</ulink> for more
                        information.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>T</title>
            <glossentry id="target-name">
                  <glossterm>target name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The address or location of a copy of a data item on a storage system.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="third-party-transfers">
                  <glossterm>third party transfers</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>In the simplest terms, a third party transfer moves a file between two
                              GridFTP servers.</para>
                        <para> The following is a more detailed, programmatic description [should be
                              in documentation somewhere-key concepts?]. </para>
                        <para>In a third party transfer, there are three entities involved. The
                              client, who will only orchestrate, but not actually take place in the
                              data transfer, and two servers one of which will be sending data to
                              the other. This scenario is common in Grid applications where you may
                              wish to stage data from a data store somewhere to a supercomputer you
                              have reserved. The commands are quite similar to the client/server
                              transfer. However, now the client must establish two control channels,
                              one to each server. He will then choose one to listen, and send it the
                              PASV command. When it responds with the IP/port it is listening on,
                              the client will send that IP/port as part of the PORT command to the
                              other server. This will cause the second server to connect to the
                              first server, rather than the client. To initiate the actual movement
                              of the data, the client then sends the RETR a?filenamea command to the
                              server that will read from disk and write to the network (the
                              a?sendinga server) and will send the STOR a?filenamea command to the
                              other server which will read from the network and write to the disk
                              (the a?receivinga server). </para>
                        <glossseealso otherterm="client-server-transfer">client/server
                        transfer</glossseealso>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="transport-level-security">
                  <glossterm>transport-level security</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Uses transport-level security (TLS) mechanisms.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="trigger-service">
                  <glossterm>Trigger Service</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>An aggregator service (in MDS4) that collects information and compares
                              that data against a set of conditions defined in a configuration file.
                              When a condition is met, or triggered, the specified action takes
                              place (for example, an email is sent to a system administrator when
                              the disk space on a server reaches a threshold).</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="trusted-ca-dir">
                  <glossterm>trusted CAs directory</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The directory containing the CA certificates and signing policy files
                              of the CAs trusted by GSI. Typically this directory is
                                    <filename>/etc/grid-security/certificates</filename>. For more
                              information see Grid security directory in the [Pre-WS A&amp;A
                              Developer's Guide ("Environmental Variables" section)].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>U</title>
            <glossentry id="uuid">
                  <glossterm>Universally Unique Identifier</glossterm>
                  <acronym>UUID</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Identifier that is immutable and unique across time and space.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="user-cert">
                  <glossterm>user certificate</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A EEC belonging to a user. When using GSI, this certificate is
                              typically stored in <filename>$HOME/.globus/usercert.pem</filename>.
                              For more information on possible user certificate locations, see
                              [Credentials in the Pre-WS A&amp;A Developer's Guide
                              ("Environmental Variables" section)].</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="user-cred">
                  <glossterm>user credentials</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The combination of a user certificate and its corresponding private
                              key.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>W</title>
            <glossentry id="web-service">
                  <glossterm>web service</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>FIXME</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="webmds">
                  <glossterm>WebMDS</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>In MDS4, WebMDS is a web-based interface to WSRF resource property
                              information that can be used as a user-friendly front-end to the Index
                              Service or other WSRF services.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsa">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Addressing</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSA</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The WS-Addressing specification defines transport-neutral mechanisms
                              to address web services and messages. Specifically, it defines XML
                              elements to identify web service endpoints and to secure end-to-end
                              endpoint identification in messages. See the <ulink
                                    url="http://www.w3.org/2002/ws/addr/">W3C WS Addressing Working
                                    Group</ulink> for details. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsdd">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Deployment Descriptor</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSDD</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>An Axis XML-based configuration file.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsdl">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Description Language</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSDL</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> WSDL is an XML document for describing Web services. Standardized
                              binding conventions define how to use WSDL in conjunction with SOAP
                              and other messaging substrates. WSDL interfaces can be compiled to
                              generate proxy code that constructs messages and manages
                              communications on behalf of the client application. The proxy
                              automatically maps the XML message structures into native language
                              objects that can be directly manipulated by the application. The proxy
                              frees the developer from having to understand and manipulate XML. See
                              the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsdl">WSDL 1.1
                              specification</ulink> for details. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsdl4j">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Description Language for Java Toolkit</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSDL4j</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>WSDL4J allows the creation, representation, and manipulation of WSDL
                              documents. For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://www-136.ibm.com/developerworks/opensource">
                                    http://www-136.ibm.com/developerworks/opensource</ulink>.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsibp">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Interoperability Basic Profile</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WS-I Basic Profile</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The <ulink
                                    url="http://www.ws-i.org/Profiles/BasicProfile-1.0-2004-04-16.html"
                                    >WS-I Basic Profile</ulink> specification is a set of
                              recommendations on how to use the different web services
                              specifications such as SOAP, WSDL, etc. to maximize interoperability.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsif">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Invocation Framework</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSIF</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink url="http://ws.apache.org/wsif/"
                                    >http://ws.apache.org/wsif/</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsn">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Notification</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSN</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The WS-Notification family of specifications define a pattern-based
                              approach to allowing Web services to disseminate information to one
                              another. This framework comprises mechanisms for basic notification
                              (WS-Notification), topic-based notification (WS-Topics), and brokered
                              notification (WS-BrokeredNotification). See the <ulink
                                    url="http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=wsn"
                                    >OASIS Web Services Notification (WSN) TC</ulink> for details.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="wsrf">
                  <glossterm>Web Services Resource Framework</glossterm>
                  <acronym>WSRF</acronym>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Web Services Resource Framework (WSRF) is a specification that extends
                              web services for grid applications by giving them the ability to
                              retain state information while at the same time retaining
                              statelessness (using resources). The combination of a web service and
                              a resource is referred to as a WS-Resource. WSRF is a collection of
                              different specifications that manage WS-Resources.</para>
                        <para>This framework comprises mechanisms to describe views on the state
                              (WS-ResourceProperties), to support management of the state through
                              properties associated with the Web service (WS-ResourceLifetime), to
                              describe how these mechanisms are extensible to groups of Web services
                              (WS-ServiceGroup), and to deal with faults (WS-BaseFaults). </para>
                        <para>For more information, go to: <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/wsrf/"
                                    >http://www.globus.org/wsrf/</ulink> and <ulink
                                    url="http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=wsrf"
                                    >OASIS Web Services Notification (WSRF) TC</ulink> .</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
      <glossdiv>
            <title>X</title>
            <glossentry id="xalan">
                  <glossterm>Xalan</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>XSLT stylesheet processor. For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://xml.apache.org/xalan-j/"
                                    >http://xml.apache.org/xalan-j/</ulink>
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xerces">
                  <glossterm>Xerces</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Advanced parsing. For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://xerces.apache.org/xerces-j/"
                                    >http://xerces.apache.org/xerces-j/</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xindice">
                  <glossterm>Xindice</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Native XML database. For more information, see <ulink
                                    url="http://xml.apache.org/xindice/"
                                    >http://xml.apache.org/xindice/</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xml">
                  <glossterm>XML</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Extensible Markup Language (XML) is standard, flexible, and
                              extensible data format used for web services. See the <ulink
                                    url="http://www.w3.org/XML/">W3C XML site</ulink> for details.
                        </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xml-db">
                  <glossterm>XML::DB</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>Provides an XML persistance layer using the postgresql database. For
                              more information, see <ulink url="http://xmldb.sourceforge.net/"
                                    >http://xmldb.sourceforge.net/</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xml-apis">
                  <glossterm>XML-APIs</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink url="http://www.apache.org"
                                    >http://www.apache.org</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xml-rpc">
                  <glossterm>XML-RPC</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink url="http://www.apache.org"
                                    >http://www.apache.org</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xmlsec">
                  <glossterm>XMLSec</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>For more information, see <ulink url="http://www.apache.org"
                                    >http://www.apache.org</ulink>. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="xpath">
                  <glossterm>XPath</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para>XPath is a language for finding information in an XML document. XPath
                              is used to navigate through elements and attributes in an XML
                              document. See the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/xpath">XPath
                                    specification</ulink> for details.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
      </glossdiv>
</glossary>
